Herbert A. Philbrick Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1849-1997 (Box 28-221)
  - Third party, 1957, undated (Box 190)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1954-1969, undated
  - Thompson, Robert, 1951-1953, 1959, 1966
  - Thomson, Meldrim, 1965-1967, 1975-1977, undated
  - Thurmond, Strom, 1962-1971, undated
  - Thying, Harison R., 1966
  - Tibet, 1959, 1965-1967, 1987
  - Tillich, Paul, 1959, 1974
  - Timber, 1961-1971, undated
  - Time magazine, 1955, 1961-1969, 1973
  - Timpson, Ann Burlak, 1958-1962, undated
  - Tito, Josip Broz, 1957-1970, undated
  - Tocsin, 1958-1966
  - Toledano, Ralph de, 1954-1956, 1963-1970, undated
  - Torchbearers of America, 1961, undated
  - Tourists, 1958-1960, undated
  - Trade, 1950-1973, 1991-1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - Treaty violations, 1959 (Box 191)
  - Treaties, 1942, 1954-1957, 1963-1972, 1979, undated
  - Tribune of Enslaved Nations, 1962-1964
  - Trujillo, Rafael L., 1959-1961
  - Trumbo, Dalton, 1959, 1970-1971
  - Truth about Communism, 1961-1964, 1970, undated, (2 folders)
  - Truth about Cuba Committee, 1961-1968, undated, (2 folders)
  - Tshombe, Moise, 1964-1969
  - Tuller, Charles A., 1972
  - Twin Circle Publishing Co., 1967-1971, undated
  - Tytell, Martin K., 1952, 1958, undated
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1933, 1952-1972, 1981, 1992, undated, (1 folder) (Box 192)
  - Ugly American, 1958-1960, undated
  - Ukraine, 1955-1975, 1991, undated, (2 folders)
  - Ukranian Bulletin, 1958-1966
  - Underground Evangelism, 1976-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Underground press, 1968, undated
  - Unidentified flying objects (UFOs), 1957, 1966-1968
  - Unions, 1952-1965, undated
  - Unitarian Church, 1951-1960, 1968, undated
  - United Cerebral Palsy Associations, 1959-1968, undated, (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box 193, Box 194)
  - United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America, 1949-1955, undated
  - United Mine Workers (UMW), 1970, undated
  - United Nations
    - General, 1949-1972, undated, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 195)
    - Special United Nations Fund for Economic Development (SUNFED), 1946-1960, undated, (4 folders)
    - UNESCO, 1951-1966, undated (Box 196)
    - UNICEF, 1958-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - United Press International (UPI), 1968-1969
  - United Republicans of America, 1967-1970
  - United States Anti-Communist Congress
    - Campus Counterattack, 1969-1970, undated, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971, undated, (4 folders); (7 folders) (Box 197)
    - Financial material, 1968-1969
    - Ideas for booklets, 1968, undated
    - Lucom, Wilson C., 1968-1971, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1967-1969, undated, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 198)
    - Philbrick, Shirley, 1968-1969, undated
    - Press releases, 1967-1970, undated
    - Promotional material, 1967-1969, undated, (6 folders)
    - School on Communism, 1968-1969, undated
    - Tax exemption, 1969
    - Washington Intelligence Report, 1967-1972, undated, (4 folders) (Box 199)
  - United States Committee for the United Nations, 1961-1964
  - United States government publications, 1952-1964, undated
  - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1953-1972, undated
  - United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), 1976-1979, undated
  - United World Federalists, 1959-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 200)
  - University of California, Berkeley, Calif., 1950, 1964-1971
  - University of New Hampshire, Durham, N.H., 1958-1965, undated
  - University Professors for Academic Order (UPAO), 1973-1976, undated
  - Uphaus, Willard, 1958-1963, undated
  - Upholsterers' International Union (UIU), 1953-1963, undated
  - Urey, Harold C., 1954-1955, 1967
  - USA (Box 201)
    - Magazine, 1954-1975, undated, (4 folders)
    - Widener, Alice, 1955-1973, undated
  - U.S. News and World Report, 1953-1960, 1966-1968
  - U.S. Press Association
    - All Church Press, 1972, undated
    - Dinsmore, Herman H., 1972-1974, undated, (2 folders)
    - Form letters, 1954-1970, 1976, undated (Box 202)
    - Kentucky Exclusive, 1971-1972
    - Miscellany, 1960, 1969-1976, undated
    - Newspaper listings, 1969
    - Rates, 1965-1973, undated
    - Subscribers, undated
    - Twin Circle Publishing Co., 1971-1972, undated
    - Washington Exclusive, 1966-1976
  - USSR, 1944-1974, 1982-1993, undated For additional material see Containers 180-182, Soviet..., (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 203, Box 204)
  - Utley, Freda, 1950-1955, 1970
  - Utt, James B., 1962-1969
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1955-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - Vanderlaan, Vera, 1966-1968, undated
  - Venezuela, 1959-1973
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars (VFW), 1951-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 205)
  - Vermont, 1950-1966, undated, (2 folders)
  - Vermont Historical Society, Montpelier, Vt., 1954-1955
  - Vidal, Gore, 1964-1973, undated
  - Vietnam
    - General, 1956-1975, 1984, undated, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 206)
    - My Lai Massacre, 1969-1972, undated
    - North Vietnam, 1956, 1965-1972, undated
    - Viet-Nam Bulletin, 1968-1972, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 207)
    - War protests, 1963-1975, undated, (4 folders)
  - Vins, Georgi, 1976, 1983-1984, undated
  - Virginia Constitutionalists, 1965-1966, undated
  - Virginia Republican Assembly, 1965
  - Virginian magazine, 1958-1959
  - Vladmanis, Alfred, 1956-1957, undated
  - Vogeler, Robert A., 1952-1953, undated
  - Voice of America (VOA), 1951-1955, 1963-1968, 1981, undated
  - Volpe, Joseph, Jr., 1953-1954 (Box 208)
  - Voronaeff, Paul, 1966, undated
  - Voskovek, George, 1950-1951, (2 folders)
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1951-1973, 1984-1987, undated
  - Walker, Edwin, 1961-1965, undated
  - Wall Street Journal, 1959-1965, 1971
  - Wallace, George, 1968-1972
  - Wallace, Henry Agard, 1948-1956, 1970, undated
  - War issues, 1914, 1934-1941, undated, (2 folders)
  - War Resisters League, 1963-1972, undated, (2 folders)
  - Warburg, James P., 1951, 1959, 1965, undated (Box 209)
  - Ward, Barbara, 1965, 1972
  - Ward, Harry F., 1935, 1960-1963
  - Warne, Colston E., 1952, 1972, undated
  - Warner, William E., 1953-1959, 1961-1971, undated
  - Warren Commission, 1963-1967, undated For additional material see Container 226, Research material
  - Warren, Earl, 1956-1971, undated
  - Washington, D.C., Reds, 1969
  - Washington Free Press, 1967-1969, undated
  - Washington Post, 1952-1959, 1967-1972, undated
  - Washington Star, 1952, 1969-1970
  - Watergate Affair, 1972-1974, undated, (2 folders)
  - Wayne, John, 1966-1967, undated
  - We, the People, 1955, 1962-1967
  - W. E. B. DuBois Clubs of America, 1964-1966, undated
  - Wechsler, James A., 1952, undated
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1958-1959, 1967-1969, undated (Box 210)
  - Weiss, John, 1965, undated
  - Welch, Robert Henry Winborne, 1957-1972, undated For additional material see Container 121, John Birch Society, (2 folders)
  - Wells, Charles, 1964
  - Weltfish, Gene, 1952, undated
  - Weniger, G. Archer, 1960-1968, 1976, undated
  - Westcott, George, 1963-1974, 1980, undated
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, 1968, 1975, undated
  - Wheat deals, 1963-1966, 1972-1973, undated
  - Wherry, Joseph H., 1962-1964, undated, (3 folders)
  - White, Harry Dexter, 1953-1956, undated (Box 211)
  - Wice, George Spencer, 1956-1957
  - Willcox, Walter F., 1952
  - Williams, Aubrey, 1957-1963
  - Williams, Claude, 1954, 1963, 1979
  - Williams, Philip A., 1954-1964, undated
  - Williams, Robert F., 1961-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - Williams, Wheeler, 1962-1965, undated
  - Willpower, 1958, undated
  - Winchell, Walter, 1952-1953, undated
  - Win Peace and Freedom through Nonviolent Action, 1966-1967
  - Winner, Harry, 1952
  - Winrod, Gordon, 1962-1963
  - Winston, Henry, 1941, 1960, 1969, undated
  - Wiremold Co., 1958-1960
  - Witt, Nathan, 1954, 1967, undated
  - Wittmer, Felix, 1952-1953, undated
  - Witznak, Ignacy Samuel, 1955-1960, undated
  - Wolfe, Bertram D., 1953, undated
  - Wolff, Karl Dietrich, 1969
  - Women, 1953, 1968-1976, 1985, 1992, undated (Box 212)
  - Women Strike for Peace, 1962-1972, undated
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1961-1966, undated
  - Women's liberation movement, 1970, undated
  - Woodbury, David O., 1963-1965, undated
  - Woods, Robert R., 1955
  - Worker, 1949-1960, 1966-1967, undated
  - World Anti-Communist League, 1968-1974, undated, (2 folders)
  - World Council of Churches, 1959-1970, 1978-1983
  - World Court, 1960, 1966, undated
  - World Federalists, 1972, undated
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth, 1962, 1968
  - World Fellowship, Inc., 1951-1960, 1980, undated
  - World Health Organization (WHO), 1957-1962, undated
  - World Marxist Review, 1964-1966, 1978-1983, undated, (2 folders)
  - World Youth Crusade for Freedom, 1966-1971, undated (Box 213)
  - Wortham, Buel Ray, 1966-1967
  - Wright, Frank C., 1953-1982, undated For additional material see Container 226, The Queer Fish, (3 folders)
  - Wright, Roberts J., 1952-1972, undated
  - Wurmbrand, Richard, 1966-1972, undated
  - Wyman, Louis C., 1953-1975, undated, (3 folders)
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., 1956, undated (Box 214)
  - “W” miscellaneous, 1949-1975, 1989-1993, undated, (4 folders)
  - X, Malcolm, 1964-1969, undated
  - “Yankee,” informant
    - 1952-1955, (4 folders)
    - 1957-1959, (6 folders) (Box 215)
    - 1960-1962, (8 folders) (Box 216)
    - 1963-1972, undated, (6 folders) (Box 217)
  - Yarushevich, Boris Dorofeyevich (“Metropolitan Nikolai”), 1955-1959, 1965, undated
  - Yankee Network, 1955-1960
  - Yeagley, J. Walter, 1969-1970, undated
  - Yerxa, Fendall, 1950-1953 For additional material see Containers 13-17, Book
  - Yoh, Bernard, 1958-1962, 1984
  - York, Pa., Gazette, 1961-1963
  - Young Americans for Freedom (Box 218)
    - General, 1961-1981, undated, (10 folders); (5 folders) (Box 219)
    - International Communism on Trial, 1967-1968 See also Container 83, Court of World Public Opinion
    - Miscellaneous branches, 1961-1972, undated
    - New Hampshire, 1962-1971, 1981, undated, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 220)
  - Young, Nedrick, 1959-1960, undated
  - Young, Patricia, 1969-1973, undated
  - Young Republicans, 1963-1969, undated
  - Young, Richard, 1992, (2 folders)
  - Young Socialist League, 1957
  - Young, Whitney M., 1966-1971
  - Younglove, Thomas A., 1951, 1962, undated
  - Youth, 1952-1965, undated, (2 folders)
  - Youth against McGovern, 1972, undated (Box 221)
  - Youth International Party (YIPPIE), 1968, 1975, undated
  - Yost, Charles W., 1968-1969, undated
  - Yugoslavia, 1951, 1959-1973, 1991-1992, undated
  - “Y” miscellaneous, 1956-1974, undated
  - Zack, Isadore, 1959-1967
  - Zborowski, Mark, 1958-1959, undated
  - Zierins, Tedis, 1967-1969, undated
  - Zimmerman, William, 1962-1963, undated
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1967-1972, undated
- Speeches and Writings, 1928-1992 (Box 221-247)
  Holograph and typewritten manuscripts, speeches, notes and jottings, research notes, related correspondence, itineraries, contracts, and newspaper clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of writing and therein by title or topic.
  - Articles, 1952-1970, 1982-1988, undated, (3 folders) (Box 221)
  - Book reviews, 1955-1958, undated
  - Books (Box 222)
    - “The Communist Attack on Religion,” with James D. Bales, unpublished, 1960-1966, undated, (11 folders); (6 folders) (Box 223)
    - I Led 3 Lives See Containers 13-16, same heading
    - “The Strange Death of President Kennedy,” with Earl Lively, not completed
      - Authors' agreement, 1965
      - Correspondence, 1963-1971, undated, (3 folders)
      - Chapter outlines, 1963, undated
      - Drafts, 1964-1966, undated, (2 folders)
      - Notes, 1964-1966, undated, (4 folders) (Box 224)
      - Philbrick writings on assassination, 1963-1964
      - Research material, 1957-1970, undated, (9 folders); (14 folders); (2 folders) (Box 225, Box 226)
    - The Queer Fish with Frank C. Wright, 1953-1957, 1967, undated
  - Debates, 1932-1933, undated
  - Diaries, 1928, 1932, 1935, (3 folders)
  - Forewords and prefaces, 1954-1967, undated
  - Letters to editors, 1952-1973, 1980-1988, undated, (3 folders)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1954-1977, 1989-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 227)
  - Newsletters
    - Dollar Hollar
      - Correspondence
        - Gockenbach, Pete, 1963-1966
        - Miscellaneous, 1963-1968
        - Loehnert, John, 1963-1966
      - Issues
        - 1963
        - 1964, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 228)
        - 1965, (3 folders)
        - 1966, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 229)
        - 1967-1968, (4 folders)
      - Mailing lists, 1963, undated
      - Miscellany, 1964, undated
    - Herb Philbrick's News Bulletin, 1965-1969, undated, (3 folders)
    - Peoples Voice, 1964-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 230)
    - Schick Razor's Edge, 1965-1968
  - Newspaper columns
    - Column lists, 1952-1957
    - Columns
      - 1952, (14 folders)
      - 1953-1954, (11 folders) (Box 231)
      - 1955
        - Jan.-Mar.
        - Apr.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 232)
      - 1956
        - Jan.-Aug., (5 folders)
        - Sept.-Dec., (2 folders)
      - 1957, (5 folders) (Box 233)
      - 1958
        - Jan.-Feb.
        - Mar. (Box 234)
      - Undated
    - Correspondence, 1951-1959, undated, (4 folders)
    - Ideas for columns, 1955-1958, undated, (7 folders)
    - Notes, 1952-1957, undated
    - Publicity, 1952-1956, undated (Box 235)
    - Reid, Ogden
      - Columns, 1951-1952, (2 folders)
      - Philbrick memoranda and other material, 1951, undated, (2 folders)
    - Research material, 1938, 1948-1958, undated, (3 folders)
    - Syndication, 1952, undated
  - Notes, 1951-1992, undated, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 236)
  - Speeches
    - Contracts
      - 1951-1960, (3 folders)
      - 1961-1972, (5 folders) (Box 237)
    - Itineraries
      - 1952-1966, (3 folders)
      - 1967-1972, 1981-1983 (Box 238)
    - Lecture bureaus, 1951-1990, undated, (7 folders); (5 folders) (Box 239)
    - Lecture requests
      - 1952-1959, (4 folders)
      - 1960-1968, 1975-1977, (7 folders) (Box 240)
    - Miscellany, 1962, undated (Box 241)
    - Notes, undated, (2 folders)
    - Promotional material, 1952-1968, 1972-1975, 1983, undated, (2 folders)
    - Recordings, 1961-1964, undated
    - Research material, 1950-1969, undated, (2 folders); (7 folders) (Box 242)
    - Speaking engagements
      - 1951
      - 1952-1960, (5 folders) (Box 243)
      - 1961, (2 folders) (Box 244)
      - 1962-1968, (5 folders)
      - 1969-1972, (8 folders) (Box 245)
      - 1973-1987, undated, (6 folders) (Box 246)
    - Texts
      - 1951-1959, (2 folders)
      - 1960-1987, undated, (6 folders) (Box 247)
    - Vouchers, 1953-1982
- Miscellany, 1886-1994 (Box 248-273)
  Appointment books, calendars, correspondence, memoranda, legal material, financial material, family papers, scripts, card files, press clippings, and printed material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or activity and chronologically therein.
  - Address books, undated (Box 248)
  - Appointment books
    - 1949-1951, (5 folders)
    - 1952, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 249)
    - 1953-1955, (6 folders)
    - 1956-1957, (4 folders) (Box 250)
    - 1960-1965, (2 folders)
    - 1966, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 251)
    - 1967, (3 folders)
    - 1968, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 252)
    - 1969, (4 folders)
    - 1970, (7 folders) (Box 253)
    - 1971, (1 folder); (6 folders) (Box 254)
    - 1972, (2 folders) (Box 255)
    - 1973, (4 folders)
    - 1974, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 256)
    - 1975-1976, (7 folders)
    - 1977-1981, (10 folders) (Box 257)
    - 1982-1987, (9 folders) (Box 258)
    - 1989-1990, (8 folders) (Box 259)
    - 1991, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 260)
    - 1992, (4 folders)
  - Biographical material
    - Miscellany, 1950-1967, 1976, 1982, 1993, undated
    - Press clippings, 1941-1984, 1991-1992, undated, (5 folders) (Box 261)
    - Publicity, 1951-1971, undated, (2 folders)
  - Calendars
    - 1950-1953
    - 1954-1977, 1986-1988, (6 folders) (Box 262)
  - Card files (Box 263)
    - Name check file, undated
      - A-F
      - G-M (Box 264)
      - N-Z (Box 265)
    - Names, 1952-1953 (Box 266)
  - Childhood material, 1931-1933, undated, (2 folders) (Box 267)
  - Church activities
    - First Baptist Church, Hampton, N.H., 1978-1984, undated
    - First Baptist Church, Wakefield, Mass., 1944-1952, 1960-1962
    - First Baptist Church, Wheaton, Md., 1968-1976, undated, (4 folders)
    - Grace Baptist Church, Somerville, Mass., 1935-1940, undated
    - Miscellany, 1962, 1983-1992, undated, 1935-1940, undated
    - Other churches, 1954-1958, 1972-1976
    - Screven Memorial Baptist Church, Portsmouth, N.H., 1988-1993, undated, (3 folders)
  - Employment, 1938-1961, 1968, 1976-1978, undated, (3 folders) (Box 268)
  - Family matters
    - Birth certificate, 1915
    - Home garden, 1942-1944
    - Philbrick, Guy (father)
      - Miscellany, 1886, 1909-1913, 1932-1937, 1943, 1951-1952, undated
      - Notebooks
        - Daily records, 1930-1950
        - Freemasons, 1912-1929, 1941
    - Philbrick, Shirley
      - Correspondence
        - Philbrick, Herbert, 1973-1989, undated
        - Miscellaneous, 1967-1982, 1993-1994 (Box 269)
      - Miscellany, 1967-1978, 1992, undated
    - Various items re family members and homes, 1957, 1966-1978, 1987-1992, undated
  - Film, television, and radio activities
    - “America's Town Meeting of the Air,” 1952
    - “Bob Siegrist and the News,” 1958
    - Harding College, Searcy, Ark., film, 1962
    - “Let Freedom Ring,” radio program, 1961, undated
    - Miscellaneous appearances, 1949-1970, 1986-1987, undated
    - National Education Program films
      - Miscellany, 1962-1966
      - Scripts
        - Communism and Morals, 1966
        - Threat of Communism series, 1963
    - “Red Report”
      - Contract, 1961
      - Correspondence
        - 1961
        - 1962-1965, (4 folders) (Box 270)
      - Miscellany, 1947, 1958-1962, undated, (2 folders)
      - Production material, 1961-1962, undated
      - Publicity, 1961-1962, undated
      - Shooting scripts, 1961-1962, (4 folders)
      - Treatments, 1962, undated, (4 folders) (Box 271)
    - “Rights and Reds, Cold War in New Hampshire,” 1992
    - “Southwest Radio Church of the Air,” 1961-1962
    - “Tonight Show,” 1969-1970, undated
    - “World War III”
      - Casca records, 1958-1960, undated, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1958-1961, undated, (4 folders)
      - Production material, 1958-1959, undated, (2 folders) (Box 272)
  - Financial records, 1939, 1954-1974, 1992, undated, (3 folders)
  - Honors and awards
    - Herbert A. Philbrick Day, 1951, undated
    - Judgeship nomination, 1959, undated
    - Miscellany, 1954-1961, undated
    - Testimonial dinner, 1951
  - Legal files
    - Attorney correspondence, 1957-1961
    - Divorce and custody, 1967-1972
    - Frankel v. Philbrick, 1949-1958, undated, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 273)
    - Real estate, 1961, 1969-1972, 1979-1983, undated
  - Office files
    - Coded names, 1963-1969, undated
    - Form letters, 1959-1965, undated
    - Memoranda to secretaries, 1954-1969, undated, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1956-1964, undated
- 2001 Addition, 1925-1993 (Box 274-290)
  Correspondence, memoranda, speeches, writings, notes, scripts, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and printed matter.
  Arranged according to the organization of the main body of the collection.
  - General Correspondence (Box 274)
    - 1945-1961, (5 folders)
    - 1962
      - Jan.-Sept., (9 folders)
      - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 275)
    - 1963-1964, (15 folders)
    - 1965
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 276)
    - 1966, (9 folders)
    - 1967
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr.-Dec., (5 folders) (Box 277)
    - 1968-1993, (3 folders)
  - Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), 1945, undated
    - Party activities, 1942-1947
    - Testimony, 1949-1959, undated See also Oversize, (3 folders)
  - I Led 3 Lives
    - Book
      - Original edition, 1951-1958, 1966-1970, undated, (5 folders)
      - Revised edition, 1952, 1959, 1965-1972, (7 folders) (Box 278)
    - Serialization, 1952, undated
    - Television
      - Miscellany, 1953-1956, undated
      - Notes, 1953-1954, undated
      - Scripts
        - No. 50, “The Guest,” July-Aug. 1954
        - No. 51, “Charity,” 1954
        - No. 53, “Fifth Amendment,” 1954
        - No. 56, “The Switch,” Aug.-Sept. 1954, (2 folders)
        - No. 59, “A Very Moving Story,” Sept. 1954, undated (Box 279)
        - No. 75, “Lost Report,” Feb. 1955
        - No. 78, “Lost Identity,” Feb. 1955
        - No. 95, “Trapped,” Oct., 1955
        - No. 96, “Mother-in-Law,” Oct. 1955
  - Subject File
    - Accuracy in Media (AIM), 1975-1981, 1987, undated
    - All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1953-1960, undated
    - American Committee for Liberation, 1957
    - American Committee to Free Cuba, 1963-1964, undated
    - American Institute, 1959-1961, undated
    - American Legion, 1957, 1963-1965
    - American Security Council, 1975-1977
    - America's Future
      - “Behind the Headlines” broadcasts, 1987
      - General, 1958-1963, 1976-1987, undated
    - Amway, 1973-1977
    - Baptist Joint Committee on Public Affairs, 1973-1976
    - Captive Nations Week, 1967, 1977
    - Cardinal Mindszenty Foundation, 1966-1970, 1976, 1983
    - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, 1962-1983, undated
    - Cohn, Roy, 1988
    - Columbia Lecture Bureau, 1954, 1963-1965, undated See also Container 280, Lecture bureaus
    - Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA), 1956-1971, undated
    - Conservatives, 1969-1975, undated
    - Constructive Action, 1967, undated
    - Country Stores, 1947-1951, 1957, undated (Box 280)
    - Cvetic, Matt, 1961
    - Czechoslovak National Council of America, 1957, 1975
    - Danielopol, Dumitru, 1971
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), 1953, 1959-1975, undated
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1951-1964, undated
    - Freedom Leadership Foundation, 1976
    - Fulbright, J. William, 1972
    - Hunter, Edward, Tactics, 1972-1975
    - Internal security, 1951, 1962
    - International Federation of Free Journalists, 1957
    - Kalish, Abraham H., 1967, 1980-1985, undated
    - Khokhlov, Nikolai, 1956, 1986, undated
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1957
    - Lecture bureaus, 1965-1971, undated See also Container 279, Columbia Lecture Bureau, (2 folders)
    - Lions Club, New Hampshire, 1958-1960, undated
    - Lukens, Donald E. (“Buz”), 1969
    - Mailing lists, undated
    - McBirnie, W. S., undated
    - McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1951, 1964-1966, undated
    - Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Co. (3M), 1959-1960, undated
    - Miscellany, 1946, 1954, 1963-1966, 1972-1977, undated
    - Morality in Media, 1975, undated (Box 281)
    - Motion pictures
      - M & P Theatres, 1933-1941, undated, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1967, 1976, undated
    - National Exchange Club, 1954-1959, undated
    - New Hampshire Seacoast Regional Development Association, 1958-1962
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1951-1958, undated
    - Newsweek, 1961-1962
    - Peaceful coexistence, 1954, undated
    - Pink Sheet on the Left, 1973-1975
    - Recht, Charles, 1926-1927, 1939, undated
    - Religion, 1956-1961, 1976, undated
    - Religious Heritage of America, 1975
    - Rostow, W. W., 1961-1971, undated
    - Russian Bible Society, 1957
    - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1975-1976
    - Spies, 1951, 1960, 1971
    - Strube, William P., 1979
    - Treml, Vladimir G., 1957
    - Underground Evangelism, 1981-1985, undated
    - United Cerebral Palsy Associations, 1961-1963
    - United States Anti-Communist Congress, 1967-1970, undated
    - United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), 1975-1976
    - U.S. Press Association, 1969-1976, undated